Finding Aid for the The James D. Squires Papers
Special Collections and University Archives
- Series I: Journalism career (1972-1989)
  - Series VI: Multimedia
    - Audiocassettes and floppy diskettes
      - 3 ½” Macintosh-formatted floppy diskettes (5 diskettes) - The Secrets of the Hopewell Box text, design, fonts and index (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Audiocassettes - interviews, campaign songs (Ross Perot presidential campaign - RESTRICTED)
      - (Box 60)
      - Interviews - KRLD interview on Perot Report, June 13, 1992 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Interviews - Pete duPont on KLIF talk show, July 8, 1992 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Interviews - P.S. Flyswatter, Roving Reporter (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Songs - Brunetti, Don and Allen Estes. “My Job Quit Me.” 1991. Screaming Vegetables Publications (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Songs - Fallo, Kasey and Eugene Gwozgz. “God Bless America (special rendition)” (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Songs - Friedland, Jerry. “VA for Perot” (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Songs - Giller, David. “Think Positive America”, “Think Positive America (Perot version)” and “I’m a Person” (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Songs - Mattson, Ed. “The Working-Class American.” Penn Street Music. (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Songs - Taylor, Virginia. “America’s In Trouble” (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Songs - Heller, David. “Radio Demo” (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Oversize
      - (Box 61)
      - Framed photograph taken at the Freedom Center, February 1983 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - First place award for makeup and design from the Medill School of Journalism at Northwestern University, 1982 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - First place award for makeup and design from the Medill School of Journalism at Northwestern University, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - (Box 62)
      - Plaque - Award for Service to Freedom of Information from National Center for FOI studies, Chicago Headline Club, Chicago Press Club, November 29, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Framed photograph of James Squires with Harvard journalism class; signed mat (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Framed photograph of James Squires at a press conference with then-President Jimmy Carter (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Framed photograph of James Squires with Watergate judge John Sirica, autographed (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - First issue of the Chicago Tribune new format printed at the Freedom Center, October 11, 1982, mounted on plaque (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Plaque - Loyola University School of Education Award of Excellence, May 8, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - (Box 63)
      - Framed cartoon, “Excellence on the run,” 1988, by Dick Locher (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Chicago Tribune, Wednesday, May 1, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Chicago Tribune, Wednesday, May 1, 1974 (copy 2) (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Chicago Tribune, Thursday, August 8, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Chicago Tribune, Friday August 9, 1974 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Tennessean reprint of James Squires’ series “Shall the Lender Get More?” n.d. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Tennessean reprint of James Squires’ series “Shall the Lender Get More?” n.d. (copy 2) (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Photographs (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Mock of Opinion page, Sentinel Star, June 28, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Galley proof of Rolling Stone article “The Crack Up,”, October 1, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Letter and certificate from Daisy Brook School (Box 63, Folder 11)
      - Photocopied maps from trip to Russia, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Map of People’s Republic of China from 1975 trip (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Copy of Shoe by Jeff MacNelly, signed (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Artwork for cover of The Secrets of the Hopewell Box, from Ruth Fecych (Box 63, Folder 15)
      - Signed original cartoon by Jeff MacNelly, signed by editorial staff (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Signed original cartoon by Jeff MacNelly, May 18, 1992 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Signed original cartoon by Jeff MacNelly, November 6, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      - Signed original cartoon by Ralph Dunagin (Box 63, Folder 19)
      - Signed original cartoon by Dick Locher (Box 63, Folder 20)
      - Press name badge from 1976 presidential primaries (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Materials Removed
    - Books
      - Chicago Tribune. The American Millstone. Edited by James Squires. Chicago: Contemporary Books, 1986. (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Gross, Ken. Ross Perot: The Man Behind the Myth. New York: Random House, 1992. (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Hollander, Richard. Video Democracy: The Vote-From-Home Revolution. Mt. Airy, MD: Lomond Publications, 1985. (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Squires, James D. ¡Chantaje a la Prensa! La Comunicación en Manos de las Grandes Multinacionales. (English title: Read All About It! The Corporate Takeover of American Newspapers.) Barcelona: Editorial Prensa Ibérica, 1994. (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Squires, James D. Horse of a Different Color. Advance reading copy. New York: Public Affairs, 2002. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Squires, James D. Horse of a Different Color. New York: Public Affairs, 2002. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Squires, James D. Horse of a Different Color. UK edition. London: Little, Brown, 2002. (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Squires, James D. Read All About It! The Corporate Takeover of America’s Newspapers. Advance reading proofs. New York: Times Books, 1993. (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Squires, James D. Read All About It! The Corporate Takeover of America’s Newspapers. Hardcover first edition. New York: Times Books, 1993. (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Squires, James D. Read All About It! The Corporate Takeover of America’s Newspapers. First paperback edition. New York: Times Books, 1993. (Box 63, Folder 10)